Gary J. Hall, Jr.

59 Oak St. Bridgeton, NJ 08302 856-332-2396 gary.hall@jennystampsup.com theghall.github.io/portfolio

Recent Projects

Identicize (2018): JavaScript app that uses a Rails API to retrieve data about an image/photo that allows the app to determine if a particular person/object has been clicked in the image. **Timely Todo** (2018): JavaScript app that allows creation of tasks with due date and priority. A task can belong to a project which itself has a due date and priority.

Your Family Utube (2017) Rails app that allows a parent to vet YouTube videos for their child. Each child has their own profile in which they can watch approved videos.

Skills

Current: Ruby, Ruby Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, jQuery, Vim, Webpack, Git, Jest, RSpec, Chrome Dev Tools, Heroku, AWS, WP-CLI, Perl

Previous: C/C++, Pascal, Fortran, Mumps, VC/M, Oracle DB, PL/SQL, Unix, Linux, VMware, CGI Scripts, 3270 Emulators, Microsoft Office

Work Experience

WordPress Administrator Independent Stampin' Up Demonstrator 2016-Present

- Decreased average page load time from 15 seconds to 6 seconds.
- Eliminated issue with recurring failure of Wordpress to publish posts.
- Recouped \$619 of costs in the first two quarters of 2018 by using WooCommerce to sell retired Stampin' Up product.
- Added \$321 in sales in the first two quarters of 2018 by using WooCommerce to sell downloadable tutorials.

Systems Engineer triVin, Inc.

1994-2002

- Eliminated timeouts caused by lack of available virtual terminals by producing a report showing terminal usage.
- Provided flexibility by learning to work with the both the client and server components of the core product.

Computer Programmer Unisys Corp.

1990-1993

Decreased work needed to maintain a software product by porting it from Pascal to C++

Education/Training

Web Development	The Odin Project	2016-2018

BS Computer Science Northeastern University 1986-1990

Agile and Scrum Foundation Course Agile Aces Feb 2018